CONNER COCHRANE

Orlando, FL 32832

Phone: 954-918-3334 | Email: cccochrane1@gmail.com

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/conner-c031 | GitHub: https://github.com/connerc11 |

Portfolio: https://conner-cochranes-portfolio.herokuapp.com/

SUMMARY

Currently a passionate FullStack Software engineer with 1.5+ years of experience in developing web applications and backend systems. I am experienced with working with small and large tems, especially with great communication skills as I have connected on teams that are overseas as well as local to my workplace. Skilled on writing clear code that is easily understandable and can be maintainable and testable. Excel in testing code as well as developing automated process for the code allowing systems to work in selenium and cucumber without needing human interaction and saving lots of time. Very familiar with user interface and am well equipt to work with front end projects that allow applications to have functioning front ends. Strengths in creativity, teamwork, solving problems, overcoming errors and building projects from ideation to execution.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Java, Java/Springboot, HTML5, CSS3, ReactJs, JavaScript, Selenium

Database: MySQL, NoSQL, MongoDB, Oracle

Other: Unit-Testing, Heroku, Bash, Git, Bootstrap, AWS Cloud

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer 1 JPMorgan & Chase

2022-Present

Tampa, FI

- Working in trade finance and exposure to code functionality that involves real time payments and active solutions.
- Involved in projects that deal with full stack development, in creating back end functionality as well as front end with Java and ReactJs.
- Integrated code functionality for automation of an application with selenium that allows for a transaction flow and process.
- Covering thousands of lines of code with unit testing and providing explanations if there
 is issues discovered in codebase

Instructional Grader Edx by 2U

2022-Present

Remote

- Grade students work on mini applications/projects that they are currently working on
- Provide ample feedback to students about issues they may have in their project, such as routing issues or variable mess ups.
- Participate in grading a variety of different assignments which keeps familiarity with different variations of code and skillset.

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

Sales Associate2017-2019United States Tennis AssociationOrlando, FI

- Executed sorting new shipments to set up for display of active tournaments.
- Amplified work ethics of fellow colleagues in order to achieve adequate results work projects.
- Influenced design of the shoe room in order to adequately fit all products neatly and stacked in a proper way for easy accessibility of the customer.
- Advised proper understanding of fundamentals for customers who were looking to begin playing tennis or that needed an upgrade on products that suited them.

PROJECTS

Trivia Brews | https://connerc11.github.io/Trivia-Brews-Project1/

- The purpose of the project is to allow people to play a fun trivia game to compete or play with their friends.
- The project completely allows people to play a randomly generated trivia game, using an API call it will be able to display the values of the trivia to the users. Worked on a majority of the front end styling, but also assisted with parts of the JavaScript where necessary. Was able to get the modals functioning, for when errors present.
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Distilled News Hub | https://github.com/connerc11/distilled-news | https://sleepy-headland-32009.herokuapp.com/

- The purpose of the project is to provide people an easy way to search for trending news articles.
- The project allows you to visit the articles as well view images while searching for the
 articles. Mainly worked on the front end of the project in React with styling using
 React-bootstrap and linking variables, as well as some backend such as working on
 functionality of signing in and out.
- CSS, ReactJs & React Bootstrap, mongoDB, GRAPHQL, NodeJs
- Project completely functions when ran remotely

Fitness Buddy | https://github.com/connerc11/Fitness-Buddy | https://fitness-buddy-2.herokuapp.com/

- The outcome of the project was to incorporate a way to save and process workout data in order to develop workouts for people.
- The project completely allows people to create a user and receive a fitness plan in order to choose a workout of their preference. Mainly worked on the front end of the project in handlebars with styling and linking variables, as well as some backend such as working on functionality of signing in and out.
- HTML, CSS, Handlebars, MySQL, NodeJS

EDUCATION

AWS Cloud Practioner Certified - Self practiced and certified
Bootcamp Certificate: University of Central Florida, Orlando, FL
A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3,
Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, NodeJs, MySQL, MongoDB, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.
Bachelor's Degree of Health-Science Pre-Clinical: University of Central Florida, Orlando, FL